Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Religious Studies, Honors Theses SC4-4209
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Religious Studies, honors theses
1991-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Religious Studies
SC4-4209
1.25 Linear Feet (17 volumes in 3 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of Religious Studies.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Department of Religious Studies.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Religion -- Study and teaching.; Student papers.; Stanford University. Department of Religious Studies
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - González, Mónica M., Voices in the wilderness: Roman Catholic Sisters struggle for justice., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Mizrahi, Kate, The Jewish reneewal movement in Boulder, Colorado., 1995? (Box 1)
  - Rapp, Andrew, The role of eroticism in Saint Bernard's sermons on the Song of Songs., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Sherman, William, Inscribing the divine: language, text, and knowledge in Ibn al-'Arabi's Fuṣuṣ al-Hikam and Nicholas of Cusa's De Visione Dei., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Nicoara, Andreea C., The Romanian Uniate Church after 1948., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Mandsager, John, The 'Eruv: a space for negotiating identity., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Albertson, David, The question mark of theology: Karl Barth's scientific theology as theological critique of the university., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Kaur, Valarie, Targeting the turban: Sikh Americans and the aversion spiral after September 11., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Carpeneti, Lia, Married virgins: an exporation of the practice of spiritual marriage., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Quall, Angela R., A description of friendship., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Kao, Grace Y., The ethical status of filial duties: a demythologization of "Filial Piety" (hsiao) in the classical Confucian tradition., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Heydemann, Elizabeth Jill Honeyrose, On the possibility of post-modern mystical Judaism: exploring the theology of Rabbi Arthur Green., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Hancock, Virginia, Creating King Bhim: Ambedkar, Buddhism, and the Mahars of Maharashtra., 2001 (Box 2)
  - Akiwenzie, Clay, Writing as ceremony: a literary analysis of the oral tradition in Leslie Marmon Silko's Ceremony., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Ferry, Sara, Purity and separation at Qumran: an internal analysis of the archaeological and textual evidence., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Matsuoka, Karen Yoshiko, An experiment with philosophy for children., 1996 (Box 2)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Neely, Simon, "Sacramental experience and the theory of friendship in the late years of Simone Weil", 2011 May (Box 1)